<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
        <rss version="0.91">
        <channel>
        <title>Election Guide - Electlist Index</title>
        <link>http://www.electionguide.org</link>
        <description>Election Guide - Electlist Index</description>
        <language>en-us</language><item>
                    <title>Electlist on 12/08/2005</title>
                    <link>newsletter.php#3</link>
                    <description>&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tanzania, United Republic Of (11/01/2005)&lt;/strong&gt; Following the death of Jumbe Rajab Jumbe, running mate on the CHADEMA party&amp;rsquo;s ticket, the mainland general elections initially slated for October 30 were postponed to December 18. This decision did not affect the semi-autonomous region of Zanzibar, where elections for the local president and parliament took place on October 30 as planned. Two days after the poll, Zanzibar&amp;rsquo;s Electoral Commission announced incumbent Amani Abeid Karume as the winner of the presidential race with 53.2% of the vote; his main competitor, Seif Sharif Hamad of the Civic United Front (CUF) obtained 46.1%. In the race for the House of Representatives, the ruling Chama Cha Mapinduzi party (CCM) won 30 seats and CUF 19. The elections were marred by widespread allegations of voting irregularities and intimidation of opposition groups.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Iraq (11/01/2005)&lt;/strong&gt; The Electoral Commission announced on October 25 the results of the October 15 referendum to approve the country&amp;rsquo;s constitution. The constitution was ratified with 78% of the votes: 7,742,796 people pronounced themselves in favor and 2,109,495 votes against the document. In order for the referendum to pass, the constitution had to be approved by a majority of the voters and not be rejected by two-thirds of the voters in three or more of Iraq's eighteen governorates. Three Sunni-dominated governorates voted against the constitution, but the share of the &amp;ldquo;no&amp;rdquo; votes was higher than two-thirds (67%) in only two of them, Anbar and Saladdeen. The approved constitution paves the way for elections for a permanent legislature on December 15, 2005.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brazil (11/01/2005)&lt;/strong&gt; Provisional figures released by the Superior Electoral Court indicate that more than 63% of Brazilians rejected the October 23 referendum on the proposed law to prohibit gun sales to civilians. The initial strong public support for the gun ban weakened with the intensification of campaigns against the ban in the weeks before the referendum. Brazil has the highest number of firearms fatalities in the world, with more than 36,000 people killed last year. An estimated 17.5 million guns are currently in Brazil, about 90% in civilian hands and half of them unregistered. Under the current legislation, any citizen 25 years old or older can buy a firearm, provided that s/he passes a background check.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Liberia (11/01/2005)&lt;/strong&gt; The National Election Commission officially announced George Weah of the Congress for Democratic Change (CDC) and Ellen Johnson-Sirleaf from the Unity Party (UP) as the two presidential candidates that will contend the run-off election slated for November 8. In the first round of presidential elections held on October 11, George Weah and his running mate qualified first with 275,265 votes (28.3%), and were followed by Ellen Johnson-Sirleaf and her vice-presidential contender with 192,326 votes (19.8%). Under the Liberian constitution, a candidate and his/her running mate need to obtain 50% plus one vote of the total valid votes cast in order to win the presidential office.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Poland (11/01/2005)&lt;/strong&gt; Final results published by the National Electoral Commission indicate Lech Kaczynski as the winner of the runoff presidential election held on October 23. Lech Kaczynski secured 8,257,468 votes (54.04%) against his opponent Donal Tusk, who obtained 7,022,319 votes (45.96%). The victory came almost one month after the Law and Justice Party, led by Lech Kaczynski&amp;rsquo;s twin brother, Jaroslaw, scored a narrow victory in the September 25 elections for Sejm and the Senate.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Egypt (09/15/2005)&lt;/strong&gt; Incumbent President Mohamed Hosni Mubarak won a new presidential term in the country's first multi-candidate presidential elections, which took place on September 7. Hosni Mubarak attained 88.57% of the vote (6,316,784 ballots), and was followed by Ayman Nour with 7.58% and Noman Gomaa with 2.93% of the vote. Voter turnout was 22.95%. International monitors were not allowed to observe the vote. Domestic NGOs were given permission to monitor the electoral process only one day before the election.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Japan (09/15/2005)&lt;/strong&gt; Prime Minister Koizumi's Liberal Democratic Party (LDP) won a landslide victory in the Lower House election on September 11. The LDP secured 296 seats, while its coalition partner New Komeito won another 31 seats. Prime Minister Koizumi called snap elections in August, after his postal reform bills were rejected in the Upper House of the Diet. Koizumi refused to allow 37 members of the LDP who voted against the reform to run as LDP candidates. With 68% of the lower house, the ruling coalition is now in a position to move forward in the disputed reform process.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Norway (09/15/2005)&lt;/strong&gt; Preliminary results of the September 12 election indicate that the opposition Red-Green alliance obtained 87 seats in the country's 169-seat assembly. The opposition alliance, composed of Jens Stoltenberg's Labor Party, Kristin Halvorsen's Socialist Left Party and Aslaug Haga's Center Party, pledged to spend more of the nation's oil revenues on welfare. Some Norwegian analysts still consider the estimated 76.1% voter turnout to be lower than desirable, although it was higher than the 75.1% turnout in the last national election in 2001.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;. Updated: </description>
                </item></channel></rss>