<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
        <rss version="0.91">
        <channel>
        <title>Election Guide - News</title>
        <link>http://www.electionguide.org</link>
        <description>Election Guide - News</description>
        <language>en-us</language><item>
                    <title>G17 Plus to run alone in Serbian elections</title>
                    <link>http://www.setimes.com/cocoon/setimes/xhtml/en_GB/newsbriefs/setimes/newsbriefs/2009/07/21/nb-05</link>
                    <description>BELGRADE, Serbia -- The G17 Plus will mobilise its voters and run alone in the next elections, deputy caucus head Vlajko Senic told Blic on Monday (J...</description>
                </item><item>
                    <title>Euro Parliament Sending Romanian-Led Mission To Moldovan Elections</title>
                    <link>http://www.rferl.org/content/Euro_Parliament_Sending_RomanianLed_Mission_To_Moldovan_Elections/1782044.html</link>
                    <description>The European Parliament has said the seven-member delegation that will monitor Moldova's parliamentary elections on July 29 will be led by a Romanian, RFE/RL's Moldovan Service reports.</description>
                </item><item>
                    <title>Japan PM apologises for failures</title>
                    <link>http://news.bbc.co.uk/go/rss/-/1/hi/world/asia-pacific/8160900.stm</link>
                    <description>Japanese PM Taro Aso apologises for his party's defeat in local polls after dissolving parliament ahead of August elections.</description>
                </item><item>
                    <title>Japan's PM dissolves parliament, calls elections</title>
                    <link>http://hosted.ap.org/dynamic/stories/A/AS_JAPAN_POLITICS?SITE=VTBRA&amp;SECTION=HOME&amp;TEMPLATE=DEFAULT</link>
                    <description>TOKYO     (AP) -- Prime Minister Taro Aso dissolved the powerful lower house of Japan's parliament Tuesday and vowed his divided ruling party will make a new start in national elections next month despite forecasts it may lose the grip it has held on the nation for most of the past 55 years....</description>
                </item><item>
                    <title>Georgian president unveils reforms</title>
                    <link>http://news.bbc.co.uk/go/rss/-/1/hi/world/europe/8160682.stm</link>
                    <description>Addressing parliament, Mr Saakashvili proposed early local elections, the direct election of mayors and a reduction in presidential powers...</description>
                </item><item>
                    <title>Hard-Line Force Extends Grip Over a Splintered Iran</title>
                    <link>http://www.nytimes.com/2009/07/21/world/middleeast/21guards.html?partner=rss&amp;emc=rss</link>
                    <description>As Iran's leaders splinter over the election crisis, the Islamic Revolutionary Guards Corps is working to crush the opposition.</description>
                </item><item>
                    <title>Mozambique: Opposition 'Riots' in Parliament</title>
                    <link>http://allafrica.com/stories/200907201592.html</link>
                    <description>Riot police were called into the Mozambican parliament, the Assembly of the Republic, on Monday when a group of deputies from the former rebel movement Renamo seized the rostrum and tried to make it impossible for the Assembly to continue its work.</description>
                </item><item>
                    <title>Bulgarian right-wing parties refuse to sign memorandum with GERB</title>
                    <link>http://www.setimes.com/cocoon/setimes/xhtml/en_GB/newsbriefs/setimes/newsbriefs/2009/07/19/nb-05</link>
                    <description>SOFIA, Bulgaria -- The centre-right Blue Coalition and the conservative Order, Law, Justice Party (RZS) refused on Friday (July 17th) to sign a memor...</description>
                </item><item>
                    <title>Iran supreme leader warns opposition to back down</title>
                    <link>http://hosted.ap.org/dynamic/stories/M/ML_IRAN_ELECTION?SITE=CAACS&amp;SECTION=HOME&amp;TEMPLATE=DEFAULT</link>
                    <description>TEHRAN, Iran     (AP) -- Iran's supreme leader told politicians Monday not to disturb the country's security in a strong warning to the opposition to back down after one of its top figures called for a referendum on the government....</description>
                </item><item>
                    <title>Mauritania: Coup Leader Elected President</title>
                    <link>http://allafrica.com/stories/200907200485.html</link>
                    <description>General Mohamed Ould Abdel Aziz, who overthrew an elected government in Mauritania 11 months ago, was himself chosen president of the country in a new election at the weekend. But four opposing candidates rejected the result.</description>
                </item><item>
                    <title>Mauritania: Coup Leader Elected President</title>
                    <link>http://allafrica.com/stories/200907200485.html</link>
                    <description>General Mohamed Ould Abdel Aziz, who overthrew an elected government in Mauritania 11 months ago, was himself chosen president of the country in a new election at the weekend. But four opposing candidates rejected the result.</description>
                </item><item>
                    <title>Khamenei blames foreign nations for Iran crisis</title>
                    <link>http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/NEWS-World-Middle-East-Khamenei-blames-foreign-nations-for-Iran-crisis-/articleshow/4798657.cms</link>
                    <description>Iran's supreme leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei on Monday accused the enemies of the Islamic republic of fomenting the crisis over last month's disputed presidential election, state television reported.</description>
                </item><item>
                    <title>Khatami calls for Iran referendum</title>
                    <link>http://news.bbc.co.uk/go/rss/-/1/hi/world/middle_east/8158692.stm</link>
                    <description>The former Iranian President, Mohammad Khatami, calls for a nationwide referendum on the legitimacy of the government.</description>
                </item><item>
                    <title>Khatami calls for Iran referendum</title>
                    <link>http://news.bbc.co.uk/go/rss/-/1/hi/world/middle_east/8158692.stm</link>
                    <description>The former Iranian President, Mohammad Khatami, calls for a nationwide referendum on the legitimacy of the government.</description>
                </item><item>
                    <title>Opposition members arrested in Myanmar</title>
                    <link>http://rss.cnn.com/~r/rss/edition_world/~3/xukED1RaowA/index.html</link>
                    <description>About 20 members of Myanmar's opposition were arrested Sunday while observing Martyr's Day, a party spokesman said.</description>
                </item><item>
                    <title>Zelaya prepares return to Honduras as talks stall</title>
                    <link>http://hosted.ap.org/dynamic/stories/L/LT_HONDURAS_COUP?SITE=CAACS&amp;SECTION=HOME&amp;TEMPLATE=DEFAULT</link>
                    <description>MANAGUA, Nicaragua     (AP) -- Ousted President Manuel Zelaya held out hope for a negotiated solution to Honduras' deepening political crisis even after talks in Costa Rica fell apart, but vowed to prepare the way for his return to power regardless of their outcome....</description>
                </item><item>
                    <title>Mega-Pro team refuse to sign election results</title>
                    <link>http://www.thejakartapost.com/news/2009/07/20/megapro-team-refuse-sign-election-results.html</link>
                    <description>Election witnesses from the Megawati Soekarnoputri and Prabowo Subianto campaign team have announced they will refuse to sign the results of official vote counting in several cities, claiming electoral fraud...</description>
                </item><item>
                    <title>Nigeria: We'll Win More States in 2011, Says Ruling Party</title>
                    <link>http://allafrica.com/stories/200907200002.html</link>
                    <description>Following serious internal crises within the party which were reported by THISDAY yesterday, the top hierarchy of the ruling Peoples Democratic Party (PDP) is making desperate efforts to assure its members that there was no cause for alarm, promising to take more states in the next general election.</description>
                </item><item>
                    <title>No deal for ousted Honduras president</title>
                    <link>http://rss.cnn.com/~r/rss/edition_world/~3/ZqnF1vypxTw/index.html</link>
                    <description>Honduras' interim government rejected a proposal to reinstate ousted President Jose Manuel Zelaya, ending a round of negotiations aimed at resolving the country's political crisis.</description>
                </item><item>
                    <title>Opponents seek to deny Karzai firstround win</title>
                    <link>http://hosted.ap.org/dynamic/stories/A/AS_AFGHANISTAN_KARZAI?SITE=NYPLA&amp;SECTION=HOME&amp;TEMPLATE=DEFAULT</link>
                    <description>KABUL (AP) -- Critics decry his government as corrupt and ineffectual, the economy is in the tank and the country is racked by an insurgency led by the very people he helped oust from power eight years ago....</description>
                </item></channel></rss>